<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CIE</title>
    <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cie-website.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CIE</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cie-website.netlify.app/media/logo_hud6de4f7a474511623ec9af12b8d43403_58349_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>CIE</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astroecology</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/astroecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/astroecology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Astroecology is a research field devoted to scientific study of the interactions of life with extreme environments even exoplanetary conditions. By applying theory, methods and technology from ecology, microbiology, molecular biology, and engineering, we aim to help solve major global challenges such as extreme climate change and space-research stuff. Astroecology is a rapidly developing field with a strong interdisciplinary aspect that holds many challenges and opportunities for scientists. Indeed, technological advances have made possible long space travels and even exoplanetary colonies in the future. Nevertheless, the success of these activities depends on our ability to produce edible plants in stressful conditions such as high radiation, extreme temperatures, and low oxygen levels. In fact, several beneficial microorganisms, such as those inhabiting extreme environments, have helped agriculture cope with those difficulties. Thus, extremophiles may be a putative tool to ensure plant growth under exoplanetary conditions. In addition, microgravity is other constraint imposed to crops in space travel, in this sense microorganisms from extreme environments would help to cope with this factor for many plants, due the switch-on of different biochemical pathways and molecular responses by part of these extremophiles. Thus, our main aims are devoted to assesses the ecological, biochemical, and molecular responses of extremophiles inhabiting from environments such as the Antarctica, High-Mountains or Atacama Desert exposed to exoplanetary conditions, to search and select microorganisms able to act as a key biotechnological tool for future space agriculture, and helping plants cope with harsh environmental conditions as those find at beyond of the Earth.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;footer&gt; 
&lt;/footer&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbial Ecology</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/microbial-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/microbial-ecology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
 section{
 background: #f8f2cc;
 margin: 0px;
 padding: 0px;
 }


 h2
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diversity and functional significance of microbial communities have become apparent in the last 20 years. Microbial and viral communities dominate nearly every habitat on Earth from the deep ocean subsurface to the mountain tops and everything in between. Microbes contribute to planetary-level processes such as element cycling and to other organisms’ homeostasis such as humans and other non-human animals and plants. While recent advances in microscopy, nucleic acid sequencing, and microbial culturing, are enabling researchers worldwide to study microbial communities in the most varied environments, we continue to learn more about processes and mechanisms that govern microbial communities, both at the community and the molecular level. Likewise, microbial ecology is maturing into a discipline concerned not only with describing patterns and inferring processes, but also with manipulating and designing microbiomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the Center for Integrative Ecology, we approach microbial ecology at different levels of organization, from molecules, to populations, to communities, and traits. We focus on extreme environments from high latitudes or altitudes including Patagonian fjords and channels and desert environments such as Antarctica and the Atacama Desert in an effort to characterize and understand phylogenetic and functional diversity locally but with global impacts.  These extreme environments offer unparalleled opportunities to untangle microbial interactions and function. In Antarctica, for instance, we study origin, phylogeny and function of soil and rhizosphere microbes, including viruses. In this environment, only two vascular plants naturally occur, which turn this environment effectively in a natural laboratory for conducting microbial ecology. In the remote Patagonian fjords and channels, little is known about composition and diversity of microbial communities, let alone their functions and emerging properties such as resilience and resistance. And in the Atacama Desert, we know a great deal about microbial community composition and structure but much less about the functions microbes and viruses encode.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In this area of research, we attempt to answer questions including but not limited to interactions between different ecosystems, populating the branches of the microbial and viral tree of life, and understanding how viruses exert control of microbial communities in terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems. Some of the questions are: How do microbial communities migrate? What is the relative contribution of soil or the phyllosphere to migration? How migrating microbes are incorporated to their new habitat? What is the coding potential of dark matter microbes and viruses? What mechanisms viruses use to bottom-up control microbial communities? What are the environmental consequences of bottom-up control for microbial services to ecosystems?
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Research topics of interest &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Host-microbiome interactions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Novel microorganisms and novel functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Spatial and temporary dynamics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Engineered and synthetic microbial communities &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Postdoctoral researchers &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/sergio-guajardo/&#34;&gt;Dr. Sergio Guajardo&lt;/a&gt; - viromes, soil communities, bioinformatics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/jorge-gallardo/&#34;&gt;Dr. Jorge Gallardo&lt;/a&gt; – botany, yeasts, in situ experiments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Graduate students &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/valentin-berrios/&#34;&gt;Valentín Berrios&lt;/a&gt; – bioinformatics, genomics, natural products, biosynthetic gene clusters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/felipe-bermudez/&#34;&gt;Felipe Bermudez&lt;/a&gt; – resilience, aquatic microbial communities, mesocosmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/cristina-munoz/&#34;&gt;Cristina Muñoz&lt;/a&gt; – bioinformatics, genomics, aquatic microbial communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/jaime-alarcon/&#34;&gt;Dr. Jaime Alarcón&lt;/a&gt; – phyllosphere, araucaria, biogeography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;International collaborators&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cbi.gwu.edu/keith-crandall&#34;&gt;Keith A. Crandall&lt;/a&gt; – The George Washington University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cbi.gwu.edu/marcos-perez-losada&#34;&gt;Marcos Pérez-Losada&lt;/a&gt; – The George Washington University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://people.miami.edu/profile/b6f6679fa2fc5c3e713597da6eca8131&#34;&gt;Amy E. Zanne&lt;/a&gt; – University of Miami&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://physiology.med.cornell.edu/people/christopher-mason-ph-d/&#34;&gt;Christopher Mason&lt;/a&gt; – Weil Cornell Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;footer&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt; Link to photography &lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qqigvuajub0ei0c/glaciarunion.031.jpeg?dl=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qqigvuajub0ei0c/glaciarunion.031.jpeg?dl=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/c34w5i5n9jd0ohe/glaciarunion02.jpeg?dl=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/c34w5i5n9jd0ohe/glaciarunion02.jpeg?dl=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noauthor Notitle Nodate 1</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/noauthor-notitle-nodate-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 12:46:50 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/noauthor-notitle-nodate-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Ecology and Evolution in Agroecosystems</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/plant-ecology-and-evolution-in-agroecosystems-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/project/plant-ecology-and-evolution-in-agroecosystems-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;

 section{
 background: #f8f2cc;
 }



&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Plants are the key as they produce most of the organic energy that sustain life and ecosystem processes on earth. This organic energy can be in live organisms or dead matter and sustain plant-based trophic food webs or detritus-based trophic webs. 
Human activities are changing the entire planet at an unprecedented rate - so there is no ecosystem out of their influence. This is more relevant under the existing compromise between producing food for a growing wealthy population settled in even bigger cities and nature conservation. 
Our interest is to investigate how plants survive, grow, and reproduce under environmental contexts characterized by the scarcity of resources (nutrients / water) and incidence of stress factors [some of natural origin (e.g., high temperatures, UV-B radiation, ozone) and others of anthropic origin (e.g., pesticides)]. In this regard, we are specifically interested in understanding what are the functions that symbiotic microorganisms fulfill in the ability of plants to accommodate / adapt to the abiotic environment and in particular, in defense against biotic threats (herbivores and pathogens). 
Never before, two big impulses lead our work and fall under the umbrella of the ecology and evolution in agroecosystems: (1) The genuine interest in understanding the drivers behind the organization of nature – from genes to ecosystems, and (2) The necessity to find solutions to the global challenges such as climate change and food security. Our research integrates plant physiology and microbiology with ecology and evolution (which involve plant interaction with biotic threats (herbivores and pathogens) and abiotic stress factors. We are a fundamental piece in the society - running research projects and forming young scientist that will be in charge of solving the coming environmental issues.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Postdoctoral researchers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/andrea-ueno/&#34;&gt;Dr. Andrea Ueno&lt;/a&gt; 2022-2024. Papel de las asociaciones simbióticas en relación maleza-cultivo bajo escenarios de cambio global: la batalla se intensifica. Postdoctoral fellowship supported by University of Talca, Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Doctoral researchers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;  
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/frank-zarraga/&#34;&gt;Frank Zarraga&lt;/a&gt; 2022-2025. Respuestas transgeneracionales en plantas mediadas por microorganismos simbióticos de transmisión vertical. Doctoral fellowship supported by University of Talca, Chile.&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Technician&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;   
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cie-website.netlify.app/authors/sebastian-gonzalez/&#34;&gt;Sebastian González&lt;/a&gt; He obtained his Doctorate in Science DBVB program at the Institute of Biological Sciences of the University of Talca, Chile. His expertise is on molecular biology. &lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;International collaborators&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utm.utoronto.ca/cue/people/marc-johnson&#34;&gt;Professor Marc Johnson (PhD)&lt;/a&gt; – Director of the Centre for Urban Environments, University of Toronto Mississauga, Canada.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utu.fi/en/people/kari-saikkonen&#34;&gt; Professor Kari Saikkonen (PhD)&lt;/a&gt; – Biodiversity Unit of the University of Turku, Finland. &lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/members/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publicaciones</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publicaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publicaciones/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation in scientific meeting of Plant Biology and Biotechnology.</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/post/participacion-en-encuentro-cientifico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/post/participacion-en-encuentro-cientifico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sixth version of the scientific meeting on plant biology and biotechnology held at the University of Talca, Campus Lircay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fungal endophytes improve the performance of host plants but do not eliminate the growth/defence trade‐off</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/atala-fungal-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/atala-fungal-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and when fungal endophytes can eliminate the plant growth–defence trade‐off: mechanistic perspectives</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/bastias-how-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/bastias-how-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating unknown species of urban microorganisms on a global scale unveils novel functional diversity and local environment association</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/wu-annotating-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/wu-annotating-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardening Blueberry Plants to Face Drought and Cold Events by the Application of Fungal Endophytes</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/acuna-rodriguez-hardening-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/acuna-rodriguez-hardening-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Soil Crusts as Ecosystem Engineers in Antarctic Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/barrera-biological-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/barrera-biological-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Physical-Chemical Soil Parameters on Microbiota Composition and Diversity in a Deep Hyperarid Core of the Atacama Desert</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/fuentes-influence-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/fuentes-influence-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting climate change-related genetic offset for the endangered southern South American conifer Araucaria araucana</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/varas-myrik-predicting-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/varas-myrik-predicting-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed functional traits in cultivars of tall fescue (Schedonorus arundinaceus) are affected by the non-toxic fungal endophyte AR584</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/riveira-rubin-seed-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/riveira-rubin-seed-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First instance of Talca MetaSUB sampling day</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sampling has been organized in Chile since 2015 exclusively in Santiago throughout different communes in order to study and represent the urban microbiome of the city. Without
However, this year 2022, at the hands of Dr. Eduardo Castro, the initiative has been extended for the first time
to a regional city of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine members of the research center were deployed through crowded urban sites in the city of Talca, taking samples of the microbiome from various surfaces in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Root endophytic Penicillium promotes growth of Antarctic vascular plants by enhancing nitrogen mineralization</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/oses-pedraza-root-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/publication/oses-pedraza-root-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cie-website.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cie-website.netlify.app/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
